Samuel John Beales

Personal details:

07432 456078

sambeales11@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-beales-614624183 DH8 0HZ

Address:

15 Derwent Dale Shotley Bridge, Consett

Profile:

Biology graduate with multiple years coding experience interested in a bioinformatician position. During my undergraduate degree I developed a solid foundation of biological knowledge, while additionally gaining expertise in the use of R for data analysis. This foundation has been built upon with my Master of research degree in which I have quickly equipped myself with a proficiency with of Python and Shell scripting. Combining computational skills and knowledge of underlying biology, I can utilize my experiences to gain valuable insight from biological datasets.

Education:

Newcastle University 19th September 2022 - 28th July 2023:

MRes Immunobiology and Bioinformatics:

Relevant Modules:

- **Bioinformatics for Biomedical Scientists**
- **Genetics of Common Disease**
- Research Skills and Principles for the Biosciences

Project and skills:

Lessons from nature- using human developmental data to inform haematopoietic organoid design.

- Extensive use of Python in Single-cell analysis pipelines
- Use of R within Python utilising Reticulate
- Shell scripting for management of a Linux virtual machine
- Containerization with Singularity

University of Huddersfield 2018-2022:

Biology (Cellular and Molecular) B.S.(Hons): Upper second

Relevant Modules:

- Research skills 2
- Genomics
- **Genomes and Evolution**

St Bede's Catholic School and 6th Form College 2011-2018:

A-level: Biology (C), Chemistry (C), Psychology (C)

AS-level: Core Maths (B) GCSE: 7 GCSEs at A-C

BTEC: 3 BTEC at pass and above

Work experience:

Placement Student, Lonza Group; 1st September 2020 – 31st August 2021

- Worked under sterile conditions in a professional microbiology lab.
- Attended regular meetings as well as coordinated my own tasks and schedule.
- Developed my ability to write methods and carry them out.
- Provided training for other members of staff on how to use new pieces of equipment.

Committee member of University of Huddersfield fencing club; September 2019-2022

- Committed to roles as the treasurer and assisting with coaching.
- Dedication to the club has developed my ability to organise and self-motivate with responsibilities such as funding applications and teaching new members.

Academic Representative, University of Huddersfield; September 2018-2020

- Worked to improve the quality of student experience, gathering feedback, attending meetings, and filing issues.
- This has developed my initiative-taking attitude to actively solve problems within the University.

Coding languages:

- Python
- R
- Shell Scripting(Unix, Z Shell)

References:

Research Supervisor:

Simone Webb

Tel: 07809449524 (email preferred) Email: simone.webb@ncl.ac.uk

Personal tutor: Gavin Clowry

Tel: +44 (0) 191 208 5981 Email: gavin.clowry@ncl.ac.uk

Research supervisor:

Tarja Kinnunen Tel: 01484 256862

Email: T.Kinnunen@hud.ac.uk